Alexander Jesse (AJ) Diaz

917-288-8084 | alexanderjessediaz@gmail.com | Website

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript-based programming with a background in sales. Studied interpersonal communication and philosophy to help better understand how people collaborate and work in a team environment. Possess strong skills in team-building and project management that help retail companies drive sales and amazing customer experience. Led multiple sales departments in training, coaching, and hiring to cultivate employees that led to promotions to full-time and management roles. Solved customer service, maintenance, scheduling, and staffing issues that occurred while supervising a retail store. An avid skier and mountain biker.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Bootstrap, Swift, Swift UI, Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, HTML

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Personal Website - Website

My personal website where I post my work as a software engineer

- Clean UI using Sanity.io to display projects
- Includes my projects, blog posts, and an about me section
- Styled with Tailwind

Zugzug Inc. Website

A web app for users who play World of Warcraft. Search for any in-game item to see price data about it.

- Users can filter to any server or faction in the game.
- Look up any in-game item to retrieve price data
- Displayed price data shows the item's performance over the course of a week.

Memories App - Github

Full CRUD application that posts cards containing images, titles, descriptions, and tags.

- Full authentication and Google Oauth option
- Dynamically renders likes, limiting users to one like per post.

EXPERIENCE

Stoke App, Intern, Boston, MA

01/2021 - 03/2021

- Worked with CEO, CTO, and lead developer on user Inbox views and constraints
- Provided insight into future features and enhanced user experience

REI, Sales Lead, Greensboro, NC & Lakewood, CO

05/2013 - 12/2019

- Promoted to Action Sports Sales Lead role in the first year of employment
- Coordinated training of 30+ employees to check in for service, sales, and orders of outdoor gear relating to skis, bikes, car racks, kayaks, leading to the highest sales in the Action Sports Department in store history.
- Responsible as a key holder for the Lakewood location. Opened and closed store, ensured cash drawers properly accounted for, responsible for scheduling, staffing, and logging incidents during a shift.
- Ensured security procedures: locked store, armed security system, closed all cash registers, and stored cash in safe.

QUEST. IT Representative. Charlotte. NC

08/2010 - 04/2012

- Provided excellent customer service when cleaning computers of the virus' and reinstalling operating systems and other computer repair tasks. Always received great feedback from clients and superiors.
- Created, submitted, and processed technical tickets related to student and faculty computer issues.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, Denver, CO

01/ 2020 - 06/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript program

Queens University of Charlotte, Charlotte, NC Bachelor of Arts (BA) Interpersonal Communications

2008-2012